时间
Time.
空间
Space.
现实
Reality.
它们不仅仅是线性的
It's more than a linear path.
而是一个拥有无限可能的棱镜
It's a prism of endless possibility,
一个选择便能开辟出无数个现实
where a single choice can branch out into infinite realities,
创造出与你所知不同的平行世界
creating alternate worlds from the ones you know.
我是观察者
I am the Watcher.
我将带领你们穿越这些新现实
I am your guide through these vast new realities.
跟随我来  并思考这个问题
Follow me and ponder the question...
假如
第一季  第七集
"假如"呢
"What if?"
给我进  这次要进
For the win. This is it.
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
这次要进  给我进
And this is it, for the win.
给我进  这次要进
For the win. This is it.
翻译    杏仁斯嘉丽  Eunice
给  我
For the...
太好了  一次就进了  简  你欠我50块
Yes! First try. Jane, you owe me 50--
翻译    Melanie_je  三四月
校对    小酸奶
简  简  简
Uh, Jane, Jane, Jane!
它在哔哔响  它哔哔响
It's beeping! It's doing the beeping!
我要与神盾局局长通话
I need to talk to the director of S.H.I.E.L.D.
时间轴    大葱
因为如果我的数据正确
Because, if my data is correct,
那么应该就会马上发生外星人入侵
I believe an alien invasion is imminent and...
后期    吉吉
喂
Hello?
两年前  伊卡洛斯阿尔法星出现了同样的反常现象
Two years ago, the same anomaly struck Star Alpha Icarus
总监    小酸奶
然后整个星体变暗  噗得一下瓦解了
and the entire star dimmed and then, poof, disintegrated.
是  我知道你们是公园管理局
Yes, I know this is the Parks Department,
但你们就不能做点什么吗
but isn't there something you can do?
这可是世界末日级别的事件  兄弟
Talking about the end of the world, my dude.
他们来了
They're here.
太迟了  入侵已经开始了
We're too late. The invasion has begun.
欢迎来到拉斯维加斯
天啊
Holy moly!
米德加德的子民们
Citizens of Midgard...
你们无聊的生活即将结束
...your dull lives are about to come to an end.
准备好
Prepare yourselves...
迎接派对王子吧
for the party prince!
会很棒的
This is gonna be awesome.
比起战争输赢
More than battles won or lost,
真正定义英雄的其实是关系
it's relationships that truly define a hero.
塑造他们的人  他们的经历
The people who shape them, their stories.
托尔和洛基  浓烈而举足轻重的兄弟情
Thor and Loki, a brotherhood so strong and pivotal,
可以改变一个宇宙的命运
it would change the fate of a universe.
托尔从他们的童年吸取了很多教训
Their childhood taught Thor many lessons.
但在另一个宇宙
But in another universe,
奥丁没有把约顿海姆的王子洛基当成亲儿子抚养
instead of raising the Jotunheim prince, Loki, as his own son,
而是将他还给了他的子民
Odin returned him to his people.
没有了他那爱耍诡计的弟弟捣乱
Without his trickster brother to keep things, let's say, lively,
托尔长成了一个迥然不同的王子
Thor grew into a very different prince.
休息吧  亲爱的
Rest, my love.
让奥丁之眠恢复和治愈你的身体
Allow the Odinsleep to restore your body and soul.
他睡着了  那么...
He's asleep. And, uh...
我要去姐妹家庆祝夏至了
I'm off to my sister's to celebrate the solstice.
这是你第一次品尝做国王的滋味  王子
Now, this is your first taste of kinghood, my prince.
我希望你学习
I expect you to study,
读读你终有一天要统治的九大王国
read up on the Nine Realms that you will one day rule.
当然  母后
Of course, Mother.
-不许办派对  -当然  母亲
- No parties. - Of course, Mother.
别忘了海姆达尔会盯着你的
Remember, Heimdall will be watching.
等等  什么  你不是认真的吧
Wait, what? You can't be serious.
听话
Behave.
海姆达尔  你在这儿啊
Oh, Heimdall, there you are.
我这就去学习  书不读不进脑子
Just off to study. Books won't read themselves.
但您的母后说
But your mother said--
别这么扫兴嘛  霍根
Don't be such a wet blanket, Hogun.
朋友们别说了  父王统治阿斯加德已经好几个世纪
Oh, guys, stop. My father has ruled Asgard for centuries.
看啊  他做过的最有趣的事
And, look, the most interesting thing
只是睡着
that he's ever done is fall asleep.
他只在乎责任职责什么的
He only cares about duty and blah-blah-blah-blah responsibility.
我可不要变得像他一样  无趣的国王  不
Well, I'm not gonna be like him, right? The boring king? Uh-uh.
但海姆达尔都看在眼里
But Heimdall sees all.
我们一有动作他就会告诉弗丽嘉
If we try anything, he'll call Frigga.
有点信心嘛
Oh, ye of little faith.
我们要去连海姆达尔都不会注意到的
We are going to the most backward, backwater planet
最落后  最与世隔绝的星球
that not even Heimdall pays attention to.
提醒各王国
Alert the realms.
在米德加德办派对
Party on Midgard!
欢迎来到拉斯维加斯
太好了
Yes!
呜呼
Huzzah!
敬派对王子托尔
To Thor, the party prince!
-欢迎  欢迎朋友们  -派对王子
- Welcome! Welcome, friends. - Party prince!
享受今夜
Enjoy the night.
雷电抱抱
Thunder hug.
来  喝一杯  酒永远喝不完
Here, have a drink. It never runs out.
你想喝完
You try to drink it all,
但你喝不完  因为这是魔法  呜呼
but you can't because it's magic! Huzzah!
呜呼  托尔  托尔  托尔
Huzzah! Thor! Thor! Thor! Thor! Thor!
那么多好莱坞电影可没告诉我会有这一幕
Hollywood movies did not prepare me for this.
不是应该有更多激光吗  探测器  会飞的奶牛
Shouldn't there be more lasers? Probing? A flying cow?
我的数据显示
According to my data,
第一个到来的外星生物是
the first extraterrestrial to arrive was...
他
Him?
我本以为他会更像...
I expected him to look more like...
更像什么  ET
Like what? E.T.?
不这么像热辣帅哥  海滩上的芭比娃娃男友
And less like a hottie McScotty, beach body Ken,
老派的A&F新品目录男模  我还能继续举例
old-school Abercrombie catalog? I could go on. Let me.
我要跟他谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to him.
我要跟外星人首次接触
I'm gonna make first contact with an alien.
还首次  半条街的人都比你早吧
First? I think half the Strip beat you to it.
你可以跟...
You can make first contact with...
我说不好  那人进行首次接触  他看着像个窝囊废
I don't know, that guy. He looks like a loser.
黑发小妞口出狂言
Big talk coming from a brunette.
我这就去  我看起来怎么样
I'm going. How do I look?
对接下来发生的事毫无准备
Completely unprepared for whatever happens next.
变成我  变成我
Oh, do me, do me.
你变成我  变成我  你也是
Yes, you do me. You do me, and you too.
你们真像我  怎么了
Oh, you guys really get me. Yes?
你在这儿啊  站在这里
Oh, there you are, all the way down there.
好小  我差点踩到你  你好吗
So tiny, I almost stood on you. How are you?
我是地球的简·福斯特博士
I'm Dr. Jane Foster of Earth.
我是阿斯加德王子托尔
Yeah, Thor, Crown Prince of Asgard.
酒  生菜沙拉  点心  你要吗
Uh, libations, crudités, baked goods?
托佩兹  我总说什么来着
Topaz, what do I always say?
我爱蛋糕
I love cake.
等等  你是托尔
Wait, wait, wait. You're Thor?
那个挪威雷神托尔
As in Thor, the Norse god of thunder?
我不知道什么马神
I don't know anything about horse gods,
但我知道怎么召唤雷电[炒热气氛]
but I do know how to bring the thunder.
好吧  我继续
Okay, moving on.
18个月以前  伊卡洛斯阿尔法星死亡
Eighteen months ago, Alpha Star Icarus died.
它消失前出现的天文现象
The astronomaly that preceded it...
-今晚又出现了  -别喝太多了
- ...happened again tonight. - Don't drink too much.
-也别喝太少  -雷电小子
- Or too little. - Hey, thunder boy.
我想问  这是你干的吗
What I'm asking is, was that you?
是  阿尔法星  那次派对可太棒了
Yes, Alpha Star. Now, that was an excellent party.
我们三天都没找到范达尔
You know, we lost Fandral for three days.
最后在一座谷仓里找到他  蜷缩在山羊宝宝旁边
Found him in a barn, curled up next to a baby goat.
可经典了  对不对  范达尔
It was classic. Isn't that right, Fandral?
我给它起名叫加里
I named him Gary.
-没错  -羊最赞啦
- Yeah, you did. - Yeah, goats!
你们杀死了一颗行星
You killed a planet.
你手里这发光盒子是什么东西
Oh, what is that light box thing you've got there?
是魔法  我好爱魔法  是你一个人造的吗
Oh, it's magic. I love magic. Did you build this all by yourself?
不好意思  我刚好是有多个博士学位的天体物理学家
Excuse me? I happen to be an astrophysicist with multiple PhDs.
得要一大帮阿斯加德人
You know, it would take a whole team of Asgardians
才能造出这种东西
to create such a thing.
你一定是天才  你是天才吧
You must be a genius. You are a genius, aren't you?
我不确定是不是天才啦  不过...
Well, I don't know about genius, but...
还有  你的眼睛
And your eyes...
所有天才的眼睛都是如此神秘幽深吗
Do all geniuses have such deep, dark eyes?
就像看着两颗星星
It's like watching the birth
在银河系边缘诞生
of two stars on the edge of the galaxy.
现在是特价时段  想来点半价玉米片吗
Well, it's happy hour. Want some half-price nachos?
好吧  鸭仔  但这可不是约会
Okay, fine, Duck. But this is not a date.
看看会怎么发展呗
Let's just see where this evolves.
放泡沫
Release the foam.
对骰子吹气
Blow on these.
老娘需要新视角
Momma needs a brand-new eye.
沃斯塔格坠机啦
Volstagg has crashed!
我现在宣布你们结为达西和怪鸭夫妻
I now pronounce you Darcy and the Duck.
好开始纹身店
魔法  科学
电话
Ah, phone.
电话  电话  别吵了
Ah, phone... Phone! Oh, shut up!
未知来电
简·福斯特博士
Dr. Jane Foster?
来了  来了
Coming. I'm coming.
简·福斯特博士
Dr. Jane Foster!
等一下
Hold on.
简·福斯特博士  我们是神盾局
Dr. Jane Foster, this is S.H.I.E.L.D.
如果你不开门  我们就...
If you do not answer, we will--
什么事
Yes?
我们找到她了  长官
We have her, ma'am.
我是玛丽亚·希尔  神盾局代理局长
Maria Hill, Acting Director of S.H.I.E.L.D.
你得跟我们走
You need to come with us.
能不能等我先吃完早餐
Can this wait until after breakfast? 'Cause...
你是第一个警告我们有外星威胁的人
You were the first to warn us about this extraterrestrial threat.
现在我希望你会是消除威胁的关键人物
Now I hope you will be the key to eliminating it.
"威胁"  你真觉得他是威胁吗
"Threat"? Would you call him a threat, really?
你想知道我为什么是代理局长吗  福斯特博士
Do you wanna know why I am the Acting Director, Dr. Foster?
不行
Nope.
大玩咖  这虽然是你的派对
Hey, Spicoli. This might be your party,
但这里不是你的星球
but this isn't your planet.
在有人受伤之前  我需要...
Before someone gets hurt, I need...
深水炸弹
Ball cannons!
-他没事吧  -仍然昏迷不醒
- Is he okay? - He's still unconscious.
要不要点吃的
We getting food?
屋里还有别人吗  福斯特博士
Do you have company, Dr. Foster?
是一个朋友
Uh... A friend.
你们快看  洗手池里有只可爱的小兔子
Guys, guys, look. There's a cute little rabbit in the sink.
瞧这小兔子  多漂亮啊
Oh, look at this little rabbit. It's gorgeous.
他是...动物学家  我再联系你  好吗
He's... a zoologist. I'll call you, okay?
我全都告诉你了
I told you everything.
我追踪异常的起源  到了拉斯维加斯
I followed the anomaly's origin to Vegas.
然后你做了什么
And then what did you do?
局长  派对气氛似乎蔓延开来了
Director, the party atmosphere seems to be spreading.
加拿大  蒙古  甚至是宾州荷兰郡
Canada, Mongolia, even Pennsylvania Dutch country.
由主要煽动者  阿斯加德的托尔领头
Led by the main instigator, Thor of Asgard,
他现在已经飞走了
who's now taken to the skies.
什么  他走了
What? He left?
他...他有没有留下字条
Did he... Did he even leave a note at...
我是说  他有没有说他去哪儿了
I mean, did... Did he say where he was going?
-转得真"不硬"  -多谢了
- Smooth. - Thanks.
-我是讽刺你  -巴黎
- Sarcasm. - Paris.
他一个同伙的原话是  "馋可丽饼了"
One of his compatriots was, and I quote, "Jonesing for crepes."
长官
Ma'am...
最后手段到了
the last resort has arrived.
等一下  "最后手段"  听起来没转弯余地了
Whoa, whoa. "Last resort" sounds very final.
这可是地球第一次接触到外星生命
This is Earth's first encounter with alien life.
今天的应对方式将为我们和外星的外交关系
How we respond today will set the tone for diplomatic relations
定下好几代的基调
between our worlds for generations.
"外交关系"
"Diplomatic relations"?
现在的年轻人都用这种词吗
Is that what the kids are calling it?
你错了  博士
You're wrong, Doctor.
这不是神盾局第一次遭遇外星人
This isn't S.H.I.E.L.D.'s first alien rodeo.
传呼机  我爸有一部  他是足病医生
A beeper? My dad has one! He's a podiatrist.
等等  你们要呼叫足病医生吗
Wait, are you guys calling a podiatrist?
发送中
完成了
It's done.
正在发生吗  有发生吗  我错过什么了
Is it happening? Did it happen? What'd I miss?
好  来吧  都贴近一点
All right, here we go. Nestle on in.
-所有人说"华夫饼"  我喜欢这词  -茄子
- Everyone say "Waffles." I love that word. - Cheese.
上面浇了枫糖浆和鲜奶油的华夫饼
Waffles with maple syrup and whipped cream on top.
-托尔  -托尔
- Thor! - Thor!
他来了  他来了
He came! He's here!
女巫的那个混蛋儿子  托尔·奥丁森在哪
Oi! Where's that son of a witch, Thor Odinson?
你说什么
What did you say?
范达尔  那根丑爆的冰棍是在跟我说话吗
Fandral, tell me, is that butt-ugly popsicle stick talking to me?
-击个拳  -你居然来了
- Bring it on in. - I can't believe you came!
洛基  你真是最棒啦
Loki, you are the absolute best!
你就是我的异母兄弟  我真心这么认为
You're my brother from another mother, man. I mean that.
-真心的  -一辈子的好兄弟
- I mean it. - Brothers forever.
一辈子的好兄弟
Brothers forever!
一辈子
Forever!
等等  怎么有闷响  你是不是放屁了
Wait, what's that boom? Did you boom?
我没放屁  你有放吗  你经常放屁
No, I didn't boom. Did you boom? You always boom.
我从来不放  我只在私下放
I never boom. I only boom in private.
洛基  快看  是流星  赶紧许愿
Oh, oh, oh. Loki, look, it's a shooting star. Make a wish, quick!
对  是流星  好  我希望...
Yes, yes, a shooting star. Yes, okay. I wish... I wish...
法国
我希望  我希望  我希望
I wish, I wish, I wish... I wish...
-我想到了  -什么愿望  告诉我
- Uh... I've got it! - What is it? Tell me.
我怎么能告诉你  说出来会不灵的
I couldn't possibly tell you. It'll ruin the magic.
白蛇  我们得谈谈
Hey, Whitesnake. We need to chat.
我叫托尔  写法是TROH
The name is Thor, with a "T" And an "R" and an "O" and a "H."
但不是按这个顺序
But not in that order.
-你办的派对不错  -根本是最精彩的
- Quite some party you're throwing. - Isn't it the best?
我本来希望冰霜兄弟们能来
I mean, I'd hoped the Ice Bros would show,
但洛基居然亲自驾到  洛基王子耶
but Loki himself? Prince Loki?
你开玩笑吗  我怎么可能错过
Are you kidding? I wouldn't miss this for the world.
听着  收拾好这烂摊子  然后离开这星球
Listen, bud, clean up this mess and leave this planet.
什么  不要  我喜欢这里  人人都喜欢我
What? No, I like it here. Everyone likes me.
我们玩得超开心  直到你出现了
We're having a great time... till you showed up.
派对结束了  哥们
Party's over, pal.
是吗  我倒有个想法
Mmm. Yeah, maybe here's a thought.
不如你滚蛋吧
Uh, how about you just buzz off?
这不是请求  万人迷
I wasn't asking, hotshot.
米德加德有个词用来形容你这种女人
You know, there's a Midgardian word for women like you.
扫兴鬼
Party pooper.
没错  我就说了
There. I said it.
好吧  这一拳是替弗瑞出气
Okay, this one's for Fury.
剩下的人...
Now, for the rest of you...
吃我一锤
Have at you!
出手挺利落  但你...
Smooth move, bro. You just--
回旋锤  懂了吗
Hammerang. Get it?
听着  伙计  我数到三
Look, pal, I'm gonna count to three
你把锤子放下
and you're gonna put the hammer down.
来了  来了
Oh, here we go. Here we go.
和你说什么来着  停手
Hey, what did I tell you? Knock it off.
英国
停下  这些都是...
Hey, quit it. These are...
我也不知道这些是什么
I don't know what these are.
没人知道  但是...不  我说不行  停
No one does. But... No! I said no! Stop.
但我只需要轻轻这么一下
Oh, but I just have to do a little boop.
完了  你的怪石头都倒了
Oh, no, your weird rocks have all fallen over.
派对出丑
Party foul.
马上就来  再等一秒
Be right with you. Just one second.
来了  开打
Ah, there it is. Whoo! Let's do this.
你猜怎么  我开始有点...
You know, I'm starting to...
不许揪头发
Ow! Not the hair!
你知道你需要什么吗
You know what you need?
一杯烈酒  外加夏威夷度假两周
A stiff drink and two weeks in Hawaii?
需要暂停
A time-out.
我妈经常用暂停来惩罚我
My mother punished me with time-outs all the time,
但对我从来没用
but I never learned a thing.
但也许对你有用  因为你是派对扫兴者
But maybe they'll work on you because you're a party pooper.
大家来看啊  这是个派对扫兴者
Hey, look, everyone! A party pooper.
扫兴者  扫兴者  扫兴者
Pooper! Pooper! Pooper!
弗瑞说你是最棒的
Fury said you were the best.
一拳能抵十颗核弹
That your punch was equal to ten nuclear bombs.
你的猫还能吞掉整支部队
That your cat could devour whole armies.
你还有只猫  它叫什么
You've got a cat? What's its name?
咕咕
Goose.
顶级飞行员  你可真特立独行
Oh, Top Gun! You're Maverick!
你的自尊是否太大但能力却跟不上
Is your ego writing checks that your skills can't cash?
-没有  -是的
- No. - Yes.
-你是哪位  -达西  你的大粉丝
- Who are you? - Darcy. Big fan.
顺便说句  本来以为你是个男队长
By the way, totally thought you were gonna be a dude captain.
但看看你  完全不是
But look at you, all not.
如果我使出全力  会在地球炸出一个大坑
If I exert my full powers, I blow a crater in this planet.
制服KK疯男并不值得冒这么大伤亡风险
Taking down Kappa Kappa frat freak won't be worth the fatalities.
那在南达科塔怎么样
Ooh. What about South Dakota?
或者北达科塔呢
Or North Dakota?
未知来电
我要接个电话
Uh... I need to get this.
你需要实习生吗  驯猫人呢
So, uh, do you need an intern? Cat wrangler?
达西  现在你热情过于高涨
Darcy, right now, you're running at an eight,
我需要你稍微冷静一下  可以吗
and I need you to take it down to a four. Okay?
-喂  -简
- Hello? - Jane!
我什么时候可以再见到你
When can I see you again?
你是我遇到过的最善良最美丽的米德加德女人
You're the nicest, prettiest Midgardian woman I've ever met.
你遇到过多少个地球女人
How many Earth women have you met?
两个  但另一个用一座桥砸我
Uh, two. But the other one hit me with a bridge
然后  疼的可不只是脸
and, well, that hurt more than my face.
托尔  和我实言相告
Thor, be honest with me.
你在阿尔法星的最后一次派对上
At your last party on Alpha Star,
是真的毁掉了那颗星球吗
did you really destroy that planet?
没有  没  那也不是星球  最多就是颗流星
No, no, it was more of a meteor anyway, not a planet.
而且它也正在燃烧殆尽
And it was burning apart
所以我们也就帮着推了一下...
so we just kinda helped it along and...
所以并没人受伤害
So no one got hurt?
-当然没有  -福斯特博士
- Of course not. - Dr. Foster?
哪怕那只小山羊  加里  都安全回家
Even the baby goat, Gary, got home safely.
-最终回家了  -福斯特博士
- Eventually. - Dr. Foster.
我得走了  爱你
Uh, I gotta go. Love you. Oh.
我是想说  再见
I mean, bye.
我们之前在说什么来着
What were we talking about?
我想说的是
Look, all I'm saying is,
就算你炸飞一个达科塔  也没人会注意到
no one would notice if you blew up a Dakota.
说真的  我根本分不清它俩
Honestly, I can't tell them apart.
南达科塔在北达科塔下面
South Dakota is on the bottom.
这个主意不错
It's not a bad idea.
莫哈维沙漠可以承受那个程度的攻击
The Mojave Desert could withstand the hit.
把他引到西伯利亚  然后直接炸飞
Lure him to Siberia and then go kaboom on his ass.
你不是认真的吧  我们不会把他炸飞
You're not serious. We're not gonna kaboom him.
我们说的可是整个星球的命运
We're talking about the fate of the planet.
他是有点呆  没错
He's a lughead, sure,
也并不是最招人喜欢的那个
and far from the brightest crayon in the box.
但这个计划太过激进  我不会让它发生
But this plan is way over the top, and I refuse to let it happen.
谢谢你的专业指导  福斯特博士
Thank you for your expertise, Dr. Foster,
但我们已经不需要你的协助了
but your assistance is no longer required.
该死  我和银河女王蜂的实习计划也泡汤了
Damn! There goes my internship with the Galactic Queen Bee.
看是谁步履蹒跚的回来了  这不是鸭夫人吗
Well, look who came waddling back. Mrs. The Duck.
-现在不是吵架的时候  霍华德  -喂  托尔
- Not now, Howard! - Hello, Thor?
-你是谁  -我是简  你能听到吗
- Who's this? - It's Jane. Can you hear me?
稍等  是那女孩吗  托尔的新甜心  喂
Wait. Is this the girl? Thor's new sweet lady? Hello.
托尔在吗
Is Thor there?
午夜吃中餐最棒了  我爱食物
Late-night Chinese is the best. Oh, I love food.
洛基  你这个蓝家伙赶紧滚过来
Loki, get your blue butt over here.
一定要尝尝这些饺子
You have to try these dumplings.
地球女孩  你有朋友吗
Hey, Earth girl. You haven't got a friend, have you?
我们可以来个双人约会
You know, we could double date.
真恶心  你能赶快把手机给他吗
Ugh! Will you just put him on the phone?
不要因为点小事就不高兴  他就在...
Oh, don't get your knickers in a twist. He's right here... Oh!
完了
Oh. Right.
喂  洛基
Hello? Loki?
小心我的羽毛
Hey, hey. Watch the feathers.
-可惜我们不能给他妈打电话  -什么
- Too bad we can't call his mom. - What?
一般不都是这样吗
That's what always happens.
年轻人开派对  嗨过了头
Teenagers throw a party, it gets out of control...
你可真是个天才
Oh, you really are a genius.
现在看起来就是这样的  我刚才说什么了
It's really starting to look that way, isn't it? What'd I say?
如果有托尔和洛基
If there's a Thor and a Loki,
那肯定有奥丁  弗丽嘉和海姆达尔
then there must be an Odin and a Frigga and a Heimdall!
他和谁来着
Uh, he-man-who-now?
你看  我也有王冠  我们还都喜欢火
You know, I've got a crown too, and we both like fire, right?
来嘛  把你那火点上
Come on. Let's see you turn up the heat on this thing.
看看几点了
Uh... Ooh, look at the time.
我能弯多低呢
How low can I go?
各位  看我从那个尖东西上滑下去
Everyone! Watch me slide down that pointy thing.
咱们走
And away!
连上这个  绿色亮了  好  很好  就绪
This one goes here. Green in the thing. Okay, sweet. Good to go.
塞尔维格  谢谢你
Selvig, thank you.
重新排列卫星  放大信号强度
Re-aligning the satellites, magnifying the signal.
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
-没起作用  -好  好  到我了  我来
- It's not working. - Okay, okay. My turn. I got this.
那辆海军蓝色普锐斯的车主  能不能...
Would the owner of the navy blue Prius...
你好  所以  关于托尔...
Hi. So, uh, about Thor...
不怎么样  我可感觉到疼了
Not cool. I actually felt that one.
-我们已就位  -装备核弹
- We're in position. - Arm the nukes.
什么  我以为她才是那核弹
What? But I thought she was the nuke.
以防万一她被猫分神
Just in case she gets distracted by a cat.
...你好  奥丁夫人
Uh... Hello, Mrs. Odinwife?
那是霞多丽酒吗
Uh, is that Chardonnay?
算是变种  是的  有什么可以帮你
A varietal, yes. Can I help you?
你为什么坚持要破坏我的乐趣
Why do you insist on crushing my mellow?
放松  享受一下  稍微笑一笑
Huh? Loosen up. Have fun. Smile a little.
随时可以开火  长官
Ready to fire on your command.
开火倒计时  五...
Fire in five...
我警告过你了  我用拳头警告过你了
I gave you a warning. Hell, I gave you a warning punch.
-四  -是托尔  他有麻烦了
- Four. - It's Thor. He's in trouble.
-三  -他在地球
- Three. - He's on Earth.
二
Two.
-惊奇队长怎么办  -她不会有事的
- What about Captain Marvel? - She'll be fine.
一
One.
托尔  阿斯加德的王子
Thor, Crown Prince of Asgard,
奥丁的独生子  你在干什么
only son of Odin, what are you doing?
-母亲  -母亲
- Mother! - Mother?
母亲
Mother?
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
为了关注我的行踪  你肯定用了不少黑暗魔法
You must be using a lot of dark magic just to check in on me.
有人来找我  她很担心你
Ugh, I had a visitor. She's worried about you.
什么...  简把我出卖了
Wha... Jane sold me out?
她说你在米德加德
She said you were on Midgard.
她弄错了
Well, she is mistaken.
我很显然在我房间里  学习
I'm obviously in my room, studying.
不要对你的母亲撒谎
Do not tell falsehoods to your mother.
你是说地球啊  抱歉  我理解错了
Oh, you mean Earth. Sorry, I misunderstood.
当地人管这里叫地球  是的  没错  对不起
The locals call it that. Yes, right. Sorry.
我一时之间没听懂
Confused there for a moment.
我和学习小组的伙伴们过来进行文化交流
Me and my study group came down here for a cultural exchange.
"文化交流"
"Cultural exchange."
你知道我们这种人  渴望知识的战士
You know us. We're warriors for knowledge.
真的吗  那我得亲自看看
Hmm. Really? Then this I have to see for myself.
我要提前结束行程
I'm cutting my trip short.
你要来这里
You're coming here?
我可爱的儿子  我希望
And, my sweet son, I expect
我到达的时候能看见你的全套学习计划
to see your full syllabus when I arrive.
机会难得  希尔
Now or never, Hill.
退下  我们结束了
Stand down. We're done here.
我们永远没有机会发射核弹了
We never get to fire the nukes.
我差点都要替你难过了  美人儿
I almost feel bad for you, Blondie.
求你了  你得帮帮我  我母亲要来了
Please, you must help me. My mother is coming.
想听我的建议吗  从角落开始往外清洁吧
My suggestion? Start in the corners, clean your way outward.
角落  角落
Corners, corners...
但这是个球体啊
But it's a sphere.
抱歉了  女士们  我得提前离开了  又一次
Ugh. Excuse me, ladies. I'm sorry, but I must leave early. Again.
洛基  我的弟弟  我需要你的帮助
Loki, my brother. I require your assistance.
我早就抢先一步了  小雷雷
Ah, one step ahead of you, Tiny Thunder.
我们哥几个打算在圣路易斯  圣...还是叫路易
My bro's trying this thing in St. Louis. Saint... Is it "Louie"?
不管怎么说  我们打算
Anyway, we're about to make
制造宇宙里最大的弹弓
this universe's greatest slingshot.
好好享受你们在这里的时光吧
Try to enjoy the rest of your time here.
一千年以后见  海姆达尔
See you in another thousand years. Heimdall.
不玩弹弓了  不搞破坏了
No more slingshots. No more destruction.
我们得把这些清理一下回家去
We need to clean this mess up and go home.
马上
Ugh! Now!
干得漂亮  我差点信了
Ha! Nice one. Almost fell for it.
我没开玩笑  我母亲要来了
I'm not joking. My mother is coming.
但她不是我母亲
But she's not my mother.
我只是跟你情同兄弟而已  记得吗
You know, I'm your brother from another mother, remember?
来吧  冰人们  咱们走
Come on, Ice Bros, let's go.
等等  你不能走  看看这地方
Wait. You can't leave. Look at this place.
我们对这个地方有责任  你得把这些清理了
We have a duty to this planet. You need to clean it up.
"责任  清理"  你的语气和奥丁一样
"Duty, clean"? Ugh, you sound like Odin.
什么
What?
冰人们  咱们闪人
Ice Men, let's bounce.
好了  大家听着  派对结束了
All right, listen, party's over.
你们不一定非得回家  但是不能留在这里
You don't have to go home, but you can't stay.
等等  你去哪  回来
Wait, where you going? Come back.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
你们得留下  我们需要把这里清理干净
You do have to stay here, and we need to clean up.
看看现在是谁在扫兴了
Look who's pooping the party now.
是你  你在扫兴
It is you! You are pooping the party.
你们去哪  回来
Where you going? Come back!
走  托佩兹  我们乘风而去
Let's go, Topaz. We shall ride like the wind.
-拜托了  等等  -废物
- Please! Wait. - Loser.
而且我们把小车车也带走
And we're keeping the scoot-scoots.
各位  求你们了  帮帮忙  你  你怎么样
Guys, please. Help, I... You. How about you?
我听见我爸给我打电话了  祝你好运
Uh... I think I hear my dad calling. Good luck.
各位  拜托了  大家得留下帮忙啊
People. Beings. Please, everyone, you must stay and help.
众神之父  赐予我力量
Allfather, give me strength.
你们听我说
You will listen to me.
我的母亲要来了
My mother is coming.
-弗丽嘉  -她不开心
- Frigga? - And she is not happy.
非常不开心
Like, at all.
她非常生气
She's really mad.
行啊  宝贝
Yeah, baby.
托尔最棒
意大利
托尔
Thor.
你好  母亲  看见你很高兴  欢迎来到我的学习小组
Oh, hello, Mother. Good to see you. Welcome to our study group.
大家和我母亲打个招呼
Everyone say hello to Mother.
你好  弗丽嘉妈妈
Hello, Mother Frigga.
在我们学习结束前  我们通常会怎么说来着  同学们
And to end our studies, what do we always say, class?
学习是有魔力的
Learning is magic.
看  我都跟你说我是在做教育文化交流了
See? I told you I was on an educational and cultural exchange.
你知道米德加德是斯努吉的出生地吗
Did you know that Midgard is the birthplace of the Snuggie?
母亲  你不相信
Mother, you doubt?
看看我们学了多少东西
But look at all this learning, huh?
托尔  这里是你想要的
Thor, here's the information
关于人类文明的信息
you requested on human civilizations.
我还下载了一些纪录片  PBS特别节目  NPR的播客等等
And I loaded a few documentaries, PBS specials, NPR podcasts.
我下星期给你打电话讨论
I'll call you next week to discuss it.
这么小但是里面装了这么这么多  谢谢
So tiny yet contains so, so much. Thank you.
你一定是弗丽嘉  我是惊奇队长
You must be Frigga. I'm Captain Marvel.
我知道你是谁  谢谢你帮助教育我的儿子
I know who you are. Thank you for helping educate my son.
-走吧  亲爱的  -等等
- Let's go, darling. - Wait.
差点忘了
Almost forgot.
母亲  我可以解释
Mother, I can explain.
谢谢
Thanks.
你找我母亲告状
You called my mother on me.
这么做可一点不酷
That wasn't a cool thing to do,
但是这么做是正确的  所以  谢谢
but it was the right thing. So, thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我会给你打电话  酷吗
I'll call you? Cools?
不  这不叫  "酷吗"
No, it is not "Cools."
不
No?
我还以为我们之间有点什么  我真的很喜欢你  简
But I thought we had something. I really like you, Jane.
不仅仅因为你是个天才
And not just because you're a genius.
你还非常有魅力而且...
You're also very attractive and...
那就约我出去啊
Well, then, ask me out on a date.
简·福斯特  我很荣幸能够约你出去
Jane Foster, it would be my honor to take you on a date.
在你回答之前  我想说
Before you answer, let me say
我知道一个地方全是独角兽
that I know a whole planet full of unicorns.
连侍者都是独角兽...
Even the waiters are unicorns...
-非常完美  -听起来不错  八点钟来接我
- It's wonderful. - Sounds delightful. Pick me up at0800?
一个世界是秩序恢复了  爱情萌发
A world restored, love blossoming.
正如人类和阿斯加德的儿童所说的那样
As children, both human and Asgardian, say,
他们一起幸福地生活下去直到永远
together, they lived happily ever after.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
亲爱的  也许我话说得太早了
Oh, dear. Perhaps I spoke too soon.